

Chris Lee

Full-stack Mobile Development Engineer



Singapore

Developer since 2008, at the age of 19.

+10 years of experience working in mobile applications & websites, who has participated in multiple projects.

Chris also has a particular passion for JavaScript based libraries and frameworks like React Native, Angular, React.js and Node.js







Work Experience

Full-stack Development Engineer • 1st Nations Mortgage



Maintain multiple live websites & mobile apps developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery,

PHP, Ruby, and Node.js/React.js/ReactNative

Ensure that all websites are bug-free and easy to use.

Ruby on Rails: https://easyrefi.me/

MERN stack web app: https://app.commissionpaypro.com/

React Native mobile app: https://appadvice.com/game/app/payyus/955630207

MERN Stack Developer • Legably

February 2018 - September 2018

https://www.legably.com/

- *Developed a job market platform in Node.js with MongoDB and React.js.
- *Created the "Payment Integration" using Chargebee
- *Integrated Stripe API to make payments
- *Developed admin dashboard to manage users, projects
- *Developed a messaging app using Socket.io

React Native Developer • Coinfalcon Cryptocurrency marketplace

August 2016 - February 2017

https://coinfalcon.com/en/

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/coinfalcon-buy-bitcoin/id1396963260

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.coinfalcon.mobile&hl=en&gl=US

- *Led the team that engineered and created Veelo's iOS and Android apps using React Native.
- *Developed, maintained REST APIs
- *Implemented the mobile responsive design
- *Assisted new developers







Developed and maintained a web application in Angular2

Integrated REST APIs for Antera CRM.

Developed and maintained the Antera CRM Software

Understood the CRM concept like Leads/Opportunities/Orders

Used Angular Fuse template http://angular-material.fusetheme.com

Mobile Frontend Engineer/Lead • Almosafer



February 2014 - January 2016

https://www.almosafer.com/en

https://apps.apple.com/app/id928866584?platform=iphone

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.travel.almosafer&hl=en&gl=US

Built the first generation of Almosafer mobile iOS/Android app

*

Served as the architect and technical lead for the front-end development of the Almosafer hotel booking mobile application in early 2014. The new mobile app included the following main features like Search and Evaluation, Selection, and Booking. The search engine used the following parameters to get optimized search results.

- 1) Destination (city),
- 2) Dates (check-in/checkout dates)
- 3) Number of people (adults, children)
- 4) Number of rooms

*

Built the view of the results module that lists the hotels that match the initial parameters. Ratings and price for rooms, also filters and sorting based on budget, reviews, reservation policy.

k

Built the screen which shows accommodation details including Overview, Photo gallery, Amenities, Special offers, Review, Map, Room status

*

Built the completed payment process for customer's booking. It leads a user through an easy and safe transaction via our app. Integrated credit card, PayPal payment APIs.

*

Integrated Google analytics, test flights, some other third party libraries like Mixpanel, advertising SDKs and TripAdvisor.

Freelance Mobile iOS/Android Developer • Upwork, formley oDesk



April 2011 - February 2014

https://www.upwork.com/

- *Learned about mobile app development through self-study in early *Joined oDesk to start building small scale of mobile apps in
- *Worked on various types of mobile apps using Xcode/Objective-C, and Eclipse/Java
- *Built +20 apps for almost of freelancing career

Education

MALAYSIA-JAPAN INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (MJIIT)

Information Technology

Product	Language
Competitor analysisBusiness research	ChineseEnglish
	Competitor analysis

Powered by **CakeResume**